Akintunde Jegede Software Engineer

- Email:jegedeakintunde@gmail.com
- Linkedin
- Github
- Stackoverflow

Career Objective

I am a Full Stack Software Engineer with a passion for building resilient code bases that offers the best of user experience and satisfaction. I have multiple years of experience building consumer facing software with a proficiency in Node, Typescript, Git, Linux, Graphql and RESTful APIs.

Major Skills

- Languages: <u>Javascript</u>, <u>Typescript</u>, <u>Python</u>, <u>Php</u>
- Frameworks/Libraries: NodeJs, ElectronJs, ReactJs, ReactNative, Graphql (Apollo)
- Databases: MongoDb, Postgresql, Mysql
- Testing: Cypress (E2E), Jest
- Others: DOCKER, GIT

Experience

FavDoctor

Lead Full Stack Developer (Remote/Part-time) | Mar. 2020 - Present | Nigeria

- Worked On An Health-Quiz Application Using React Native
- Led A Team of Developers on a Self-Diagnosis Health Application

Stack: Typescript, Javascript, ReactNative, HTML, CSS

AcceleratorApp

Backend Developer (Remote/Full-Time) | Aug 2019 - Mar. 2020 | Canada

- I built a Zapier app with multiple endpoints that allowed clients to automate information retrieval from their profiles.
- I built a Google Authentication System that allowed users authenticate their login and registration process.
- I did extensive work on an event management system that allowed auto-matching of users based on time availability.
- and more...

Stack: Typescript, Nodejs, MongoDb, Jest, Cypress

Radical Stack Limited

Software Engineer (Remote/Full-Time) | Mar. 2019 - Jul. 2019 | UK - I built multiple blockchain-based Application Program Interfaces that made use of decentralized data in creating applications that needs high level of security and data immutability.

Stack: Javascript, Nodejs, MongoDb, Posgresql, Mysql

Bitmama.io

Backend Engineer (Remote/Full-Time) | Nov. 2018 - Mar. 2019 | Nigeria

- I had the responsibility of working on the Nodejs/MongoDb/Redis Powered Codebase, which involved working on a direct-to-cash semi-matching engine for CryptoCurrency Trading.

Stack: Javascript, Nodejs, MongoDb, Posgresql, AWS

Utopian.io

Open Source Contributor | Jan. 2017 - Dec. 2018 | Nigeria

- Made code contributions and wrote technical articles for open source projects
- Built Open Source tools for Graphene-Based Blockchain Projects Stack: PHP, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Nodejs

Freelancing

Full Stack Web Developer | Jan. 2012 - Nov. 2018 | Nigeria

- I worked on an In-Office Task Management System
- I built an app that helped to calculate the most profitable NASDAQ stock to buy (Short & Medium term) using their RSI indicator and Stochastic Index.
- I built a social network that had a profile, messaging and multifeatured news system
- and more..

Stack: PHP, NodeJs, ReactJs, Laravel, AWS, HTML, CSS

Projects/ Experiments

Fashion Styles App

- This Android App helps users pick from a gallery of fashion styles. It features about 400 pictures of fashion styles that get synced offline with the android app from a nodejs server, thus allowing the user to have offline access to fashion styles with or without internet connectivity.
- Built With: React Native, Typescipt, NodeJs
- Github Link: Fashion App Repo

BlockChain Notifier

- This script notifies a blockchain user of recent transactions happening on his Steem Blockchain Account. It is meant to help an crypto-exchange have a real time notification system of activities happening on their blockchain account.
- Built With: Javascript, NodeJs
- Gitlab Link: Blockchain Notifier

Countdown Timer App

- This is a simple android app that allows a user have set up a time countdown. It features a sound alert that beeps close to the completion of the timer. It also has a feature that helps to speed up the timer twice or 1.5 times faster.
- Built With: React Native, Typescipt
- Github Link: Countdown App Repo

Social Network for Quote Lovers (Defunct)

- This website allowed users post quotes , like quotes, search quotes, create profiles , and automatically convert quotes to pictures using an algorithm based on PHP-GD library.
- Built With: PHP, HTML, JAVASCRIPT, MYSQL
- Github Link: Social Network Repo

Education

Bachelor of Engineering, Civil Engineering (2016) Federal University of Technology, Akure